The Director - Human Resource

Zambia Revenue Authority

Human Resource Department

P. O. Box 35710

Lusaka

RE: Application for a job as Assistant ICT Officer Operations

Dear Sir/Madam,

I am applying for the IT Assistant position I saw posted on Go Zambia jobs for Assistant ICT Officer Operations at Zambia Revenue Authority. The attached resume has a complete look at my work experience and training but here are a few highlights of my career so far.

I have a bachelor's degree in Computer Management and one year of experience working as an IT Assistant where I held a position at the help desk. My responsibilities included answering phone calls, emails and using live chat to provide support for network users. I have experience configuring hardware and software, tracking inventory and developing contingency plans to use in the event of a network failure. My experience also includes operating office equipment such s fax machines, copies, processing mail, preparing data spreadsheets, graphs and charts.

I have the ability to keep accurate documentations for all services I provide and I always offer friendly and professional customer service. I have the ability to assist with upgrades and to perform regular maintenance checks to ensure systems are functioning properly. I have excellent organizational and multi-tasking skills and the ability to work independently or with a team. I possess excellent research skills, the ability to evaluate and solve problems and the ability to make good decisions when working under pressure. I recently graduated from University in September and waiting for my documents to be processed next month.

I would like to meet with you in person to discuss this position in more detail and how I can be a great addition to your team. An intern position is also ok because all I want is to gain more experience. Please call (+260)-973-414167 to set up an interview.

Respectfully,

Joshua Chabe.

Joshua N. Chabe

Phone: +260 - 9673 – 91952 **Address:** Lusaka, Zambia

Email: joshuachabe02@gmail.com Date of Birth: January 25, 1998.

OBJECTIVE

Customer-focused professional who uses excellent communication and problem-solving skills to quickly and courteously resolve customer issues. Provides wide range of experience in providing technical support to end users in Lean manufacturing, quality driven manufacturing environment.

Seeking a challenging career with a progressive organization that can benefit from my technical skills and abilities in the field of information technology (IT).

SKILLS

- Hardware troubleshooting
- Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Outlook, Active Directory, Syteline.
- Network troubleshooting
- Programming (Java, C++, Visual Basic, Android Programming Language)
- Microsoft Office
- Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, InDesign, After Effects, Dreamweaver)
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills
- Highly organized and efficient
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team
- Proven leadership skills and ability to motivate

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information and Computer Management (2018 – 2022)

Bachelor of Science with Education in Mathematics (2020-2022)

Rusangu University

Southern province, Monze.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Information Technology Assistant

Swift Corporations (April 2021 - May 2020)

 Performed help desk troubleshooting and problem resolution for end-user application software, hardware, and remote access connectivity supporting over 100 personal computers.

- Maintained server rooms in two manufacturing facilities.
- Responded to helpdesk calls and documented solutions.
- Trained users in PC hardware/software and networks.
- Handled all network documentation, drawings, IP address assignments, and logging.
- Maintained all phone system hardware and software, as well as network and mainframe security.
- Performed software updates; ensured all purchased software was in compliance with licensing requirements.

Network support (Intern)

Simon Mwansa Kapwepwe Airport (August 2019 – Oct 2019)

- Provided Level 1 network support
- Assisted in installing of an upgraded network system and controlled network traffic.

IT and Math Teacher

Tick School. (May 2021 - August 2021)

- Provided Level 1 assistance
- Taught secondary level math and Computer Studies.
- Formulated lesson plans to achieve the objective.

.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.





Rusangu University PARTIAL TRANSCRIPT OF RESULTS

P O Box 660391, TEL: 260 3 255471 **MONZE - ZAMBIA**

Student Name.: Joshua Ngaluka Chabe

StudentID No.:20161015

Study.:Bachelor of Arts in Computer Management Information System with Education

Major.: BA Ed Computer and Management Information Systems

Minor.: Mathematics - Minor

Sex.: Male

OURSE CODE	COURSE TITLE	Grade	Credits	Points
CCT 111	FUNDAMENTAL TO ACCOUNTING I	C	4	8
ACCT1120	FUNDAMENTAL OF ACCOUNTING II	D	0	0
EDFN 112	EDUCATIONAL AND PROFESSIONAL ETHICS	c	4	8
EDTE 118	INFORMATION AND COMPUTER TECHNOLOGY IN EDUCATION	c	3	6
ENGL 111	INTRODUCTION TO WRITING SKILLS	C+	3	6.99
GEWE 101	GENERAL WORK EXPERIENCE	S	0	0
MATH 181	BUSINESS ALGEBRA	B+	4	13.32
OFTE1240	KEYBOARDING	s	0	0
PSYC1010	INTRODUCTION TO PSYCHOLOGY	D	0	0
TOTAL POINTS			18	42.31
GRADE POINT A	VERAGE (GPA)			2.35
CUMULATIVE G	RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		18	2.35
DECEMBE	R 2016 - JANUARY 2017 RESULTS			
CONV 100	CONVOCATION	Grade	Credits	Points
MATH 121	DISCREET MATHEMATICS	S	0	0
TOTAL POINTS	PIOCEST PETITION TO	C+	4	9.32
	VCD + CD (CD+)		4	9.32
CDADE DOINT AT				
GRADE POINT A	VERAGE (GPA) RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)			2.33

	ANY ALTERATIONS WILL RENDI	ER THIS DOCUMENT INVALID
Administration of the second	(D).	REGISTRAR

REGISTRAR: Cala

Mrs. Earlymay Chibende

Page 1 of 6



Rusangu University PARTIAL TRANSCRIPT OF RESULTS



P O Box 660391, TEL: 260 3 255471 MONZE - ZAMBIA

APRIL - M	AY 2017 RESULTS			
COURSE CODE	COURSE TITLE	Grade	Credits	Points
ACCT 112	FUNDAMENTAL OF ACCOUNTING II	В	4	12
CONV 100	CONVOCATION	s	0	0
HLED 110	HEALTH PRINCIPLES	c	3	6
PHYS 105	CONCEPTS OF PHYSICAL SCIENCE	c	3	6
RELT 206	CHRISTIAN BELIEFS I	C+	3	6.99
TOTAL POINTS			13	30.99
GRADE POINT A	VERAGE (GPA)			2.38
CUMULATIVE G	RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		35	2.36
AUGUST -	SEPTEMBER 2017 RESULTS			
COURSE CODE	COURSE TITLE	Grade	Credits	Points
CONV 100	CONVOCATION	s	0	0
COSC 240	DATA COMMUNICATION AND NETWORKS	В-	4	10.68
EDFN 102	PRINCIPLES OF CURRICULUM	F	3	0
ELCT 111	BASIC ELECTRONICS	C+	4	9.32
TOTAL POINTS			11	20
GRADE POINT A	VERAGE (GPA)			1.82
CUMULATIVE G	RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		46	2.23
ELCT 111 TOTAL POINTS GRADE POINT A CUMULATIVE G	BASIC ELECTRONICS VERAGE (GPA)	C+	11	,
DECEMBE	COURSE TITLE	Grade	Credits	Points
CONV 100	CONVOCATION	s	0	0
INSY 263	FILE MANAGEMENT AND DATABASE DESIGN	В-	4	10.68
INSY 336	MICRO COMPUTER APPLICATIONS	С	4	8
PSYC 302	EDUCATIONAL PSYCHOLOGY	c	3	6
RELT 107	CHRISTIAN BELIEFS II	C+	3	6.99
TOTAL POINTS			14	31.67
GRADE POINT A	VERAGE (GPA)			2.26
	RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		60	2.24

ANY ALTERATIONS WILL RENDER THIS DOCUMENT INVALIDE CISTRAR

REGISTRAR: Collo

Page 2 of 6





Rusangu University PARTIAL TRANSCRIPT OF RESULTS

P O Box 660391, TEL: 260 3 255471 MONZE - ZAMBIA

COURSE CODE	COURSE TITLE	Grade	Credits	Points
COMM 113	COMMUNICATION SKILLS	В-	3	8.01
CONV 100	CONVOCATION	S	0	0
COSC 161	PROGRAMMING USING C++	C+	4	9.32
COSC 162	DATA STRUCTURE AND ALGORITHMS	В-	4	10.68
COSC 255	Course-code Missmatch	С		0
EDAD3300	POLITICS OF EDUCATION	F	0	0
EDFN 216	CURRICULUM DEVELOPMENT AND IMPLEMENTATION	С	3	6
EDPC 221	EDUCATIONAL GUIDANCE AND COUNSELLING	c	3	6
EDPC 410	EDUCATION AND PSYCHOLOGY OF THE EXCEPTIONAL CHILD	C+	3	6.99
INSY 228	COMPUTER ETHICS	C+	4	9.32
TOTAL POINTS			24	56.32
GRADE POINT A	VERAGE (GPA)			2.35
CUMULATIVE C	GRADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		84	2.27
AUGUST - COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 241	SEPTEMBER 2018 RESULTS COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION JAVA PROGRAMMING	Grade S	Credits 0	Points 0
COURSE CODE CONV 100	COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION JAVA PROGRAMMING			0 8 8
COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 241 TOTAL POINTS GRADE POINT A	COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION JAVA PROGRAMMING	s	0	8 8 2
COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 241 TOTAL POINTS GRADE POINT A CUMULATIVE G	COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION JAVA PROGRAMMING VERAGE (GPA)	s	0 4 4	0 8 8 2
COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 241 TOTAL POINTS GRADE POINT A CUMULATIVE G	COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION JAVA PROGRAMMING EVERAGE (GPA) EVERAGE (GPA) EVERAGE POINT AVERAGE (GPA) EVERAGE POINT AVERAGE (GPA) EVERAGE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)	s	0 4 4	0 8 8
COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 241 TOTAL POINTS GRADE POINT A CUMULATIVE O DECEMBE COURSE CODE CONV 100	COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION JAVA PROGRAMMING EVERAGE (GPA) ER 2018 - JANUARY 2019 RESULTS COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION	s c	0 4 4 88	0 8 8 2 2.26
COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 241 TOTAL POINTS GRADE POINT A CUMULATIVE G DECEMBL COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 308	COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION JAVA PROGRAMMING EVERAGE (GPA) ER 2018 - JANUARY 2019 RESULTS COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION OBJECT ORIENTED DESIGN AND PROGRAMMING	S C	0 4 4 88	0 8 8 2 2.26
COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 241 TOTAL POINTS GRADE POINT A CUMULATIVE O DECEMBE COURSE CODE CONV 100	COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION JAVA PROGRAMMING EVERAGE (GPA) ER 2018 - JANUARY 2019 RESULTS COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION	S C Grade S	0 4 4 88 Credits 0	0 8 8 2 2.26 Points
COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 241 TOTAL POINTS GRADE POINT A CUMULATIVE G DECEMBR COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 308 COSC 2800 EDTE 322	COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION JAVA PROGRAMMING EVERAGE (GPA) EVERAGE (GPA) EVERAGE (Grade S C+	0 4 4 88 Credits 0 4	0 8 8 2 2.26 Points 0 9.32
COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 241 TOTAL POINTS GRADE POINT A CUMULATIVE G DECEMBR COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 308 COSC 2800 EDTE 322 HIST 100	COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION JAVA PROGRAMMING IVERAGE (GPA) RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA) ER 2018 - JANUARY 2019 RESULTS COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION OBJECT ORIENTED DESIGN AND PROGRAMMING LANS AND WANS	Grade S C+ D	0 4 4 88 Credits 0 4 0	0 8 8 2 2.26 Points 0 9.32
COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 241 TOTAL POINTS GRADE POINT A CUMULATIVE G DECEMBR COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 308 COSC 2800 EDTE 322	COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION JAVA PROGRAMMING EVERAGE (GPA) EVERAGE (GPA) EVERAGE (Grade S C+ D	0 4 4 88 Credits 0 4 0 3	0 8 8 2 2.26 Points 0 9.32
COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 241 TOTAL POINTS GRADE POINT A CUMULATIVE O DECEMBE COURSE CODE CONV 100 COSC 308 COSC2800 EDTE 322 HIST 100 TOTAL POINTS GRADE POINT A	COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION JAVA PROGRAMMING EVERAGE (GPA) ER 2018 - JANUARY 2019 RESULTS COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION OBJECT ORIENTED DESIGN AND PROGRAMMING LANS AND WANS INSTRUCTIONAL MEDIA AND TECHNOLOGY HISTORY OF WORLD CIVILIZATION	Grade S C+ D	0 4 4 88 Credits 0 4 0 3 3	Points 0 9.32 0 6

ANY ALTERATIONS WILL RENDER THIS DOCUMENT INVALID STRAR

PO REGISTRAR: Cola

Mrs. Earlymay Chibende

Page 3 of 6

DATE: 7. APR 202





Rusangu University PARTIAL TRANSCRIPT OF RESULTS

P O Box 660391, TEL: 260 3 255471 MONZE - ZAMBIA

	AY 2019 RESULTS	Grade	Credits	Points
COURSE CODE	COURSE TITLE	S	0	0
CONV 100	CONVOCATION	C+	4	9.32
COSC 461	OPERATING SYSTEMS	c	3	6
EDFN 124	HISTORICAL & COMPARATIVE STUDIES IN EDUCATION	c	4	8
INSY 317	BASIC UNIX ADMINISTRATION	1.7	11	23.32
TOTAL POINTS				2.12
GRADE POINT A CUMULATIVE G	VERAGE (GPA) RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		109	2.23
AUGUST -	SEPTEMBER 2019 RESULTS COURSE TITLE	Grade	Credits	Points
CONV 100	CONVOCATION	S	0	0
INSY 251	WEB TECHNOLOGIES	В-	4	10.68
INSY 332	SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT USING VISUAL BASIC	C+	4	9.32
MATH 161	MATHEMATICAL METHODS I	В	4	12
RELT 208	INTRODUCTION TO CHRISTIAN ETHICS	C+	3	6.99
TOTAL POINTS			15	38.99
GRADE POINT A	VERAGE (GPA)			2.6
	RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		124	2.28
DECEMBE	CR 2019 - JANUARY 2020 RESULTS			
COURSE CODE	COURSE TITLE	Grade	Credits	Points
CONV 100	CONVOCATION	S	0	0
COSC 280	LANS AND WANS	С	4	8
EDAD 330	POLITICS OF EDUCATION	С	3	6
INSY 480	SYSTEMS ANALYSIS AND DESIGN	С	4	8
MATH 125	ANALYTICAL GEOMETRY AND MATRIX THEORY	C+	4	9.32
TOTAL POINTS			15	31.32
GRADE POINT A	VERAGE (GPA)			2.09
4.	RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		139	2.26

ANY ALTERATIONS WILL RENDER THIS DOCUMENT INVALID REGISTRAR

REGISTRAR: Colo

Page 4 of 6





Rusangu University PARTIAL TRANSCRIPT OF RESULTS

P O Box 660391, TEL: 260 3 255471 MONZE - ZAMBIA

	AY 2019 RESULTS	Grade	Credits	Points
COURSE CODE	COURSE TITLE	S	0	0
CONV 100	CONVOCATION	C+	4	9.32
COSC 461	OPERATING SYSTEMS	c	3	6
EDFN 124	HISTORICAL & COMPARATIVE STUDIES IN EDUCATION	c	4	8
INSY 317	BASIC UNIX ADMINISTRATION	1.7	11	23.32
TOTAL POINTS				2.12
GRADE POINT A CUMULATIVE G	VERAGE (GPA) RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		109	2.23
AUGUST -	SEPTEMBER 2019 RESULTS COURSE TITLE	Grade	Credits	Points
CONV 100	CONVOCATION	S	0	0
INSY 251	WEB TECHNOLOGIES	В-	4	10.68
INSY 332	SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT USING VISUAL BASIC	C+	4	9.32
MATH 161	MATHEMATICAL METHODS I	В	4	12
RELT 208	INTRODUCTION TO CHRISTIAN ETHICS	C+	3	6.99
TOTAL POINTS			15	38.99
GRADE POINT A	VERAGE (GPA)			2.6
	RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		124	2.28
DECEMBE	CR 2019 - JANUARY 2020 RESULTS			
COURSE CODE	COURSE TITLE	Grade	Credits	Points
CONV 100	CONVOCATION	S	0	0
COSC 280	LANS AND WANS	С	4	8
EDAD 330	POLITICS OF EDUCATION	С	3	6
INSY 480	SYSTEMS ANALYSIS AND DESIGN	С	4	8
MATH 125	ANALYTICAL GEOMETRY AND MATRIX THEORY	C+	4	9.32
TOTAL POINTS			15	31.32
GRADE POINT A	VERAGE (GPA)			2.09
4.	RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		139	2.26

ANY ALTERATIONS WILL RENDER THIS DOCUMENT INVALID REGISTRAR

REGISTRAR: Colo

Page 4 of 6



Rusangu University PARTIAL TRANSCRIPT OF RESULTS



20161015-2022-04-27-88564

P O Box 660391, TEL: 260 3 255471 MONZE - ZAMBIA

OURSE CODE	COURSE TITLE	92200020	_	
AN ADDRESS OF THE PARTY	CONVOCATION	Grade	Credits	Points
OFN 118		S	0	0
SY 205	PHILOSOPHY OF CHRISTIAN EDUCATION	В	3	9
ATH 145	MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEM	C+	4	9.32
	SET THEORY AND LOGIC	B-	4	10.68
LATH 162	MATHEMATICAL METHODS II	В	4	12
OTAL POINTS			15	41
GRADE POINT A				2.73
UMULATIVE G	RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		154	2.3
TIGHTON	CERTIFICATION ASSAULT TO			
	SEPTEMBER 2020 RESULTS			
	COURSE TITLE	Grade	Credits	Points
EDAD 422	EDUCATIONAL PLANNING, ADMINISTRATION AND MANAGEMEN	c	3	6
ENGL 112	INTRODUCTION TO RESEARCH WRITING	В-	3	8.01
MATH 252	STATISTICS II	В	4	12
TOTAL POINTS			10	26.01
GRADE POINT A				2.6
CUMULATIVE (RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		164	2.32
	A STATE OF THE STA		164	2.32
	ER 2020 - JANUARY 2021 RESULTS COURSE TITLE	Grade		
DECEMBI	ER 2020 - JANUARY 2021 RESULTS	Grade U	Credits	Points
DECEMBI COURSE CODE	ER 2020 - JANUARY 2021 RESULTS COURSE TITLE	U	Credits 0	Points 0
DECEMBI COURSE CODE CONV 100	ER 2020 - JANUARY 2021 RESULTS COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION	U B	Credits 0 4	Points 0 12
DECEMBI COURSE CODE CONV 100 EDFN 122	ER 2020 - JANUARY 2021 RESULTS COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION SOCIOLOGY OF EDUCATION	U B C	Credits 0 4 4	Points 0 12
DECEMBI COURSE CODE CONV 100 EDFN 122 EDRM 434	ER 2020 - JANUARY 2021 RESULTS COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION SOCIOLOGY OF EDUCATION INTRODUCTION TO EDUCATIONAL RESEARCH METHODS	U B C B-	Credits 0 4	Points 0 12 8 10.68
DECEMBI COURSE CODE CONV 100 EDFN 122 EDRM 434 MATH 211 MATH 251	ER 2020 - JANUARY 2021 RESULTS COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION SOCIOLOGY OF EDUCATION INTRODUCTION TO EDUCATIONAL RESEARCH METHODS CALCULUS I	U B C	Credits 0 4 4	Points 0 12 8 10.68
DECEMBI COURSE CODE CONV 100 EDFN 122 EDRM 434 MATH 211	ER 2020 - JANUARY 2021 RESULTS COURSE TITLE CONVOCATION SOCIOLOGY OF EDUCATION INTRODUCTION TO EDUCATIONAL RESEARCH METHODS CALCULUS I Course-code Missmatch	U B C B-	Credits 0 4 4	Points 0 12 8 10.68

ANY ALTERATIONS WILL RENDER THIS DOCUMENT INVALID GISTRAR

Page 5 of 6





20161015-2022-04-27-885

Rusangu University PARTIAL TRANSCRIPT OF RESULTS

P O Box 660391, TEL: 260 3 255471 MONZE - ZAMBIA

APRIL - MAY 2021 RESULTS

COURSE CODE	COURSE TITLE	Grade	Credits	Points	
ACCT 358	ACCOUNTING SOFTWARE PACKAGES	В-	4	10.68	
CONV 100	CONVOCATION	U	0	0	
EDFN4360	SEMINAR ON INTEGRATION OF FAITH AND LEARNING	S	0	0	
EDFN4380	SEMINAR ON TEACHING PRACTICE	s	0	0	
EDTE 320	PRINCIPLES, METHODS OF TEACHING & CLASS MANAGEMENT	В-	4	10.68	
EDTE 412	CLASSROOM TESTING AND EVALUATION	В-	4	10.68	
EDTE 440	TEACHING PRACTICE	B+	3	9.99	
EDTE 453	SPECIAL METHODS IN TEACHING COMPUTER AND MANAGEMEN	A-	3	11.01	
MATH 212	CALCULUS II	C+	4	9.32	
MATH 311	CALCULUS III	С	4	8	
MATH 363	STATISTICAL PACKAGES	С	4	8	
TOTAL POINTS			30	78.36	
GRADE POINT AV	VERAGE (GPA)			2.61	
CUMULATIVE GI	RADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA)		206	2.38	

DECEMBER 2021 - JANUARY 2022 RESULTS COURSE CODE COURSE TITLE Grade Credits Points PSYC 101 INTRODUCTION TO PSYCHOLOGY C+ 3 6.99 TOTAL POINTS 3 6.99 GRADE POINT AVERAGE 3 2.33 CUMULATIVE GRADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA) 20 2.38

TOTAL COURSE CREDITS 209
TOTAL POINTS 496.6
CUMULATIVE GRADE POINT AVERAGE (GPA) 2.38
DECREE CLASS Credit

ANY ALTERATIONS WILL RENDER THIS DOCUMENT INVALID UNIVERSITY OF THE STREET TH

REGISTRAR: Colo Mrs. Earlymay Chibende

Page 6 of 6

DATE: 7-7-APR -2022